Guide to the Ithaca and Tompkins County (N.Y.) printed material, 1858-1992.
Ithaca and Tompkins County (N.Y.) printed material, 1858-1992
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ithaca and Tompkins County (N.Y.) printed material, 1858-1992.
1074
1.4 cubic ft.
Photographs, maps, brochures, booklets, programs, broadsides, invitations
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Included are photographs, maps, brochures, booklets, programs, broadsides, invitations, historical outlines, and other printed items pertaining to subjects including local politics and government, urban renewal, religion, civic and social events and organizations, musical and dramatic productions, transportation, educational institutions, and geology of the region.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Included are photographs, maps, brochures, booklets, programs, broadsides, invitations, historical outlines, and other printed items pertaining to subjects including local politics and government, urban renewal, religion, civic and social events and organizations, musical and dramatic productions, transportation, educational institutions, and geology of the region.
Broadside: "REWARD - Who Killed the Harris Family?...," 1990.
"Ithaca, New York: A General Plan" (1971) with sketches by Peter Kahn; members of the Planning Board include Edward J. Conley, Richard P. Korf, and John W. Reps. Also, environmental impact statements prepared for the Strand Theatre, 1992.
Poster relating to Wharton Studios and the 75th anniversary of movie making in Ithaca, produced by Terry Harbin, 1990
Ithaca Sign Company banner.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Conley, Edward J.; Kahn, Peter.; Korf, Richard P.; Reps, John William.
Subjects:
Churches--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Murder--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Religious institutionss--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Schools--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Theaters--New York (State)--Ithaca.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.)--History.; Ithaca (N.Y.)--Commerce.; Ithaca (N.Y.)--Politics and government.; Ithaca (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.; Ithaca (N.Y.); Ithaca (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; Tompkins County (N.Y.); Tompkins County (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.; Tompkins County (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; Tompkins County (N.Y.)--Politics and government.; Tompkins County (N.Y.)--Commerce.
Form and Genre Terms:
Maps.; Broadsides.; Photographs.; Pamphlets.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Includes collections #1074, #1158, 1214, 1219, 1861, 1864, 1872, 1897, 1915, and 2652.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Ithaca Government
Series II. Ithaca Schools, Ithaca College and Cornell University
Series III. Ithaca Businesses
Series IV. Ithaca Churches
Series V. Ithaca Organizations
Series VI. Ithaca Resources
Series VII. Miscellaneous
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Ithaca Government
  - The Anti-Saloon League of New York, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitution, By-laws..., Feb. 14, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rules and Regulations of the Board of Public Works of the City of Ithaca, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sanitary Code, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Plumbing Code, June 13, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Building Code, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rules, Regulations and Schedule of Water Rates, May 1, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - City of Ithaca, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Know Your City Government, July, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Charter City of Ithaca, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - How Can Ithaca Be Made a Better City, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ithaca 1990 A General Plan Summary, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Arthur P. Miller, Democratic nominee, Should be First Slaried Sheriff, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Before You Vote Read This, June 14, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Annual Kickoff Dinner, May 7, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - letter from Aaron Girard Minz, Oct. 28, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - letter from B.F. Lent, Oct. 28, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Tompkins County Handbook for 1931, Tompkins County Government, Sept. 1960 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Tompkins County Government, Mar. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - What the Ithaca Board of Commerce Had Done or Has Under Way, Sept. 1, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Community Service, Nov. 1917 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Ithaca Board of Commerce correspondence, Sept. 9, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Ithaca Chamber of Commerce Annual Report, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Directory Ithaca Board of Commerce, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Who's Who in the Ithaca Chamber of Commerce, 1947, 1948, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence from Charles Blood, Oct. 31, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence from Arthur P. Miller, Nov. 2, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Ithaca's Wlecome, Correspondence from John W. Baker, April 21, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Ithaca Newsletter, June 1940 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - 1968 Political Calendar (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence from Monroe M. Sweetland, Nov. 4, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence from Fred Clark, Nov. 5, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Live-Wire Items No. 1, Sept. 1911 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Ithaca Socialist News, Oct. 1911 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - What is the Young Socialist League? (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Summary Digest of Proposed Tompkins County Charter and Code, Aug. 26, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Annual Report of the Commissioners of Election, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Board of Supervisors: Tompkins County, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Proceeings of the Board of Supervisors of the County of Tompkins, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - An Abstract of the Fees of County and Town Officers, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - The Ferris-Blavelt Bill for Direct Primaries (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Primary Enrollment for year 1911 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Official Ballot for Election District No. 2. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Town of Ithaca, Nov. 7, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Information Booklet Concerning May 2, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - School Referendum, To the People of Ithaca, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Urban Area Report, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement Prepared for the Strand Theatre, Sept. 1992 (Box 3)
  - Final Environmental Impact Statement Prepared for the Strand Theatre, Dec. 1992 (Box 3)
  - The Plan for Downtown Ithaca, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Reports of the Common Council of the City of Ithaca, 1899-1904 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Charter of the City of Ithaca, 1887 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Charter of the City of Ithaca, June, 1888 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Ordinances of the Village of Ithaca, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Report on Plans for Sewering and Draining the City of Ithaca, NY, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - The American Worker: National Organ of the Industrial Democratic Party, June 1930 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Laws of New York-By Authority, Apr. 1906 and May 1908 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Enrollment of Voters: Tompkins County, 1929-1930 (Box 3)
  - Enrollment of Voters: Tompkins County, 1936-1937 (Box 3)
  - Enrollment of Voters: Tompkins County, 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - Enrollment of Voters: Tompkins County, 1938-1939 (Box 3)
  - Enrollment of Voters: Tompkins County, 1940-1941 (Box 3)
  - Enrollment of Voters: Tompkins County, 1941-1942 (Box 3)
  - Enrollment of Voters: Tompkins County, 1943-1944 (Box 3)
  - Enrollment of Voters: Tompkins County, 1944-1945 (Box 3)
  - Enrollment of Voters: Tompkins County, 1946-1947 (Box 3)
  - Enrollment of Voters: Tompkins County, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Enrollment of Voters: Tompkins County, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Enrollment of Voters: Tompkins County, 1952-1953 (Box 3)
- Series II. Ithaca Schools, Ithaca College and Cornell University
  - Handbook No. 1 Ithaca Public Schools, September 1919 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Amendment to Regulations.., June 1908 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ithaca Public Schools Evening Division, 1916-17 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Facts About the Ithaca Public Schools, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Frank David Boynton Junior High School Dedication Exercises, Oct. 25, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Commencement Frank David Boynton Junior High School, Jan. 25, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report of the Cayuga Preventorium, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Advantages of Lady Students at Cornell University Questions Regarding the Admission of Young Ladies to Cornell University (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Country Club of Ithaca, New York, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Country Club of Ithaca, New York, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Country Club, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Country Club, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - First Semi-Annual Commencement of the Empire State School of Printing, March 1, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Third Semi-Annual Commencement, Feb. 22, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Third-Semi Annual Commencement invitation, Circular Information, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fifth Semi-Annual Commencement, Feb. 20, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fifth-Semi Annual Commencement invitation, Sixth-Semi Annual Commencement Invitation, Independence at Fifty, Your Opportunity, 1923-1925 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Song Recital, Apr. 13, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 16th Annual Commencement Exercises, June 8, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 17th Annual Commencement Exercises, June 7, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Commencement 1913, June 9, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Music Festival, 1907-1924 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Tambu: A Murder Mystery, June 3-8, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - After Sixty Years A Campus, Community Asset, Twenty-four Pages Complete the Story, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - The Ithaca High School, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Ithaca High School Twentieth Annual Concert, Apr. 9, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - The Tattler, Dec. 1916 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - The Tattlerette, Jan. 1917 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Ithaca High School, Eighty-eighth Annual Commencement, June 24, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Class of 1981 announcement, Christmas Concert, Dec. 18, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - The Preparatory Schools of Ithaca, The University Preparatory School, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Horticultural School for Girls, Investing in Their Future, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - The Sturgis School Tutoring Department, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Ithaca Public Schools Brochures, 1908-1913 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Ithaca High School Dept. of Music Concert Program, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Ithaca Public Schools, Superintendent's Office Bulletins, 1928-1931 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Ithaca Public Schools, Our Point of View-Financial Statements, 1924, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Education Digest, 1930-1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Ithaca Evening School Brochures, 1926-1927 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ithaca Evening School Pamphlet, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Our Public Schools" Pamphlet, 1911-1913 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Ithaca Public Schools Courses of Study, 1922-1926 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Ithaca Public Schools: Manual of the Board of Education, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ithaca Public Schools, Our Point of View-Courses of Study and Handbook for Junior and Senior High School, June, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Ithaca Public Schools, Our Point of View (Historical Sketch), 1919 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Ithaca Public Schools, Our Point of View, 1924-1926 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Ithaca Public Schools, Our Point of View, 1927-1930 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Ithaca Public Schools, Superintendent's Office, 1927-1930 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Junior High School Manual Arts Courses, 1924-1925 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - New York State Teachers Association, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Our Proposed New School: Proposed High School Building for Ithaca, NY, March-April, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - One Postcard showing Ithaca High School (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Three Ithaca Public Schools, Handbooks, 1926, 1928-1929 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Series III. Ithaca Businesses
  - Cayuga Lake Cement Company (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A Review of the Business and Industry of Tompkins County (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Third Annual Dinner of the Medical Society of Tompkins County, Feb. 11, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Ithaca Memorial Hospital, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Ithaca Memorial Hospital By-Laws, Jan. 21, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Health Ass'n of Tompkins County Annual Report, 1956-57 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Through the Years with Red Cross in Tompkins County, Mar. 1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Our Hospital, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Some Suggestions About Ithaca and Its Business Resources, Self portrait of a Community, Feb. 20-26, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Twelve inches of information relating to the city and vicinity, not dated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - How The Ithaca Daily News Has Grown, not dated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Colonial Antique Shop, not dated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Ithaca Hotel, Glenwood Hotel, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Ithaca Savings and Loan Association, Jan. 1, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - By-Laws of the Ithaca Savings and Loan Association, Two Forms of Investment, Every Day Almanac, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - 86 Years of Banking Experience, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - J.W. Tibbets and Co. Forest City, 1901-1904 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - By-Laws of the Lake View Cemetary Co. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Artesian Well Water (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Wall Son College Shoes of college Me-who know (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Local Union No. 93 of Ithaca, Feb. 1901 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Kat-a-log of High Grade Shoes As Worn by the College Man (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Highland Park Association (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - The Plaza is the Place (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Tompkins County Farms Listed and for Sale by the Keeber and Barber Agency (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Morse Automatic Fuel-Saver (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Templux Automatic Stokers (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Michelson and Wheaton Correspondence, February 9, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - The Ithaca Telephone Co., March 26, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Instructions to Inspectors, $75,000 Ithaca Electric Light & Power Company (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Remarkable Achievement of the Ithaca Telephone Company (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence from the New York Telephone Company, Nov. 23, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Restaurant Menu on a Brown Paper Bag, "Uncle Abe's Brown Back Lunch,", 1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series IV. Ithaca Churches
  - Primary Dept. of the First Congressional Sunday School, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Financial Statement, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Weekly Announcements First Methodist Episcopal Church, Nov. 11, 1906 & April 25, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Dedication Week Banquet, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Roll and Directory of the First Presbyterian Church, Apr. 1885, 1887, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Library of the Infant Dept., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Service of Dedication, Apr. 13, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Catalogue of the Church Library, March 1905 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bulletins, March 21, 1912, Dec. 15, 1912, Apr. 2, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Service Installation of the First Unitarian Society, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - St. John's Episcopal Church, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - An Early Fifteenth Century Liturgical Easter Mass, Apr. 20, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Early Sketch of the First Methodist Episcopal Church, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - History of the First Baptist Church of Groton, NY, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Series V. Ithaca Organizations
  - Ithaca Civic Association, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Time to Give: Seventeen Reasons Sixth Annual Appeal, Nov. 15-22, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - The Savage Club By-Laws, May, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Rogues Harbor Community Club, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Annual Convention 11th District Pythian Sisters, May 14, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Club Essence presents Sophistication, June 4, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Grand Charity Reception, Dec. 8, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Annual Report of the Associated Charities of Ithaca, NY, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - A Paper Prepared by Robert H. Treman, Oct. 12, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - The Cayuga Indian Feast, May 27, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Dedication of the Abner Treman Memorial Tablet, July 4, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Trumbulls Corners Old Home Day, Aug. 26, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - The History of the American Legion, Aug. 11, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Silver Tea for Special Children's Center, June 11, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - T. Merrell Shipherd Testimonial Dinner, June 24, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Hangar Theatre's Guys and Dolls, July 3-20, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 1986 Finger Lakes On-The-Water Boat Show, May 2-3, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Bal-Masque, Mar. 25, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 50th Anniversary of Powered Flight, 1903-1953 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Community to Present, Aug. 13 and 14 Historical Pageant of Trumansburg, Ithaca Development, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Month by month in 1958: Happenings in Ithaca and Tompkins County Reviewed, United Way is more than just a fund drive (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Band Vocal and Instrumental Concert at Wilgus Hall, Oct. 21, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Ithaca Quartet Second Concert, June 11, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Pirates of Penzance by the Choral Club of Ithaca, May 18-20, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Ye Choral Clubbe, Benefit Entertainment for Sufferes in the Flood of 1905, July 12, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Concert given under the auspices of the Cascadilla Glee and Mandolin Clubs, Feb. 5, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Dedication Week Choir The Mountain Ash Male Choir at the First Methodist Episcopal Church, Jan. 20, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - H.M.S. Pinfore presented by the Ithaca Community Service Council, March 28-29, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Ithaca Opera Association Incorporated presents La Traviata, March 1-2, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - New York State Craft Fair, Aug. 4-9, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Barber of Seville by the Ithaca Opera Association, The Ithaca Journal proudly presents the United States Air Force Band of the East, Apr. 20, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Report of Half-Century Club of Tompkins County, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Voters Again Deprived of Right to Hear Truth, The Republican Party in Tompkins County, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - The Republican Party Reference Manual, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - The Civil Service of the City of Ithaca, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - One Hundredth Anniversary Cayuga Hose Co. No. 1 (May 10, 1928) (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Report of the Social Service League of Ithaca, Oct. 1907 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - The Ladies Union Benevolent Society and the Home, March 12, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - The Social Service League of Ithaca (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Federation of Women's Organizations of the City of Ithaca (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Members of the Ithaca Community Chest (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Ithaca Can Be the Nation's Greatest City, Will You Choose Ithaca: When You Are a Senior Citizen?, Give It All You've Got, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Catalogue of the Loan Exhibition of the Ithaca Branch of the New York Society of the Decorative Arts, Old-Fashioned Country Dance, Jan. 23, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - The Garden Club of Ithaca, 1922-23 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Archaeological Institute of America, Dec. 26-29, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - The Cornell Art Association list, Garden Club of Ithaca Home and Garden Show, Sept. 16, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - The Boulevard Circular, June 1878 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - To Be Tied, Tompkins County Reform League (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Charles Frohman presents the Fifteenth Century Morality Play "Everyman," The Choral Club at the Lyceum (June 12, 1895) (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Tornado Hook and Ladder Co. No. 3, 1916, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - The Cayuga Heights Park Association, Hampton Terrace, Proposal to Enlarge the Village of Cayuga Heights, N.Y. (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - First Preliminary Contest in Declamation, Feb. 18, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Troop 4 Boy Scouts of America, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - The Lakeside Monthly, Apr. 1873 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - A Report on the Camp Fire Organization, The Voice of Empire Youth, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Our Ithaca Y.M.C.A., Golden Jubilee Recognition Dinner, May 3, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - The Town and Gown Club Broadside (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1st Annual Tompkins County Fireman's Convention, Aug. 2-4, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 3rd Annual Fireman's Convention, June 12-14, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - The Postmaster's Advocate, May, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Tri-County Postmaters Association (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Knights of Pythias Banquet Pamphlets, 1924-1945 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Varna Volunteer Fire Co., pamphlets, 1954-1965 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Constitution and By-Laws and List of Members of the Business Men's Association, 1900-1904 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Eighth Annual Report of the Commissioners of the Ithaca Fire Department, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Vanguard: A Libertarian Communist Journal, July-August, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Series VI. Ithaca Resources
  - HELP Where to Turn in Tompkins County, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - HELP Where to Turn in Tompkins County, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - HELP Where to Turn in Tompkins County, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - HELP Where to Turn in Tompkins County, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - HELP Where to Turn in Tompkins County, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - HELP Where to Turn in Tompkins County, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Your Ithaca, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Automobile Guide Ithaca and Vicinity in the Heart of the Beautiful Finger Lakes Region (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Ithaca: In the Heart of the Finger Lakes Region (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Ithaca, NY in Tompkins County: Heart of the Finger Lakes Region, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Ithaca in the Finger Lakes Region the Home of Cornell University (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Glorious Ithaca Tompkins County N.Y. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Buttermilk Falls State Park (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Automobile Guide (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Trip Through Taughannock Falls State Park, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Ithaca and Its Resources, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Initial Ithacans by Thomas W. Burns, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Ithaca, N.Y. Illustrated, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Some Facts About Ithaca, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Ithaca Its Scenery and Advantages, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - George S. Tarbell correspondence, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - A.S. Fiske letter, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Cayuga Heights Notes, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - The Finger Lakes of Central New York, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - The Beautiful Finger Lakes Call You, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - The Clinton Houses' Dinner Menu, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Directory of Rooming and Boarding Houses (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence from Charles E. Cornell, Apr. 12, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Chas. B. Stanion, Description of Properties, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Ithaca Chronological Historical Events, 1939 (Box 1)
  - The Bellringer: A Publication of the Tompkins County Mental Health Association, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Transportation Miscellany, 1876-1932 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Series VII. Miscellaneous Materials
  - Identification of Erosion Surfaces in South-Central New York, Feb.-March, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - New Peridotite Dikes of Ithaca, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Pan-American Geologist, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Dikes as Possible Barriers to Migration of Natural Gas, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Artesian Well Sections at Ithaca, NY, Feb.-March, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Historic Ithaca and Tompkins County (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Blank checks of the First National Bank of Ithaca, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Constitution and By-Laws of the Ithaca Baseball Club, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - The Barn Dance, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - What is the Hinckley Foundation?, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Bus Time Table, Tempting Tear-Outs, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Art: U.S.A. The Johnson Collection of Contemporary American Painting (Box 1, Folder 39)